Sydney Lim MSCS @ UCSB

Last update: October 7, 2022

Up-to-date version of CV is available at https://sydneylim.github.io/resume

| Location | Fremont, CA |
|----------|-------------------|
| LinkedIn | <u>Sydney Lim</u> |
| GitHub | <u>sydneylim</u> |
| Email | scqlim@gmail.com |

Student pursuing an MS in Computer Science as part of a 5-year B.S./M.S. program at UC Santa Barbara. Aiming to leverage a proven knowledge of agile development, prototyping, product design, and R&D skills to land a software engineering position.



Professional Experience

Jun 2022 - Sep 2022

Software Engineering Intern

- · Worked closely with a small team on full-stack software development using Ruby on Rails and React.js.
- Practiced agile software development skills and consistently participated in pair programming, standups, retrospectives, and backlog
 refinement.

Ruby on Rails Full Stack Development Agile Software Development React.js RubyMine

Aug 2021 - Sep 2021

Data Loss Prevention (DLP) Intern

- · Worked on a data loss prevention project with a goal to pinpoint sources of and minimize internal threats.
- Implemented robotic process automation (RPA) script to automate data extraction in Python.
- Utilized Microsoft Power BI, Tableau, and SQL to compile, cleanse, analyze, and present the data.

Python | Microsoft Power BI | Tableau | SQL | Robotic Process Automation (RPA)

Jun 2019 - Sep 2019

Summer Intern

- Designed a database in MySQL/PostgreSQL. Utilized Microsoft Power BI to cleanse a user database.
- Designed and presented a prototype UI for the database in a pre-production environment.
- Researched natural language processing and data warehouses (Amazon AWS, Microsoft Azure, Google BigQuery).



Projects

T.A.L.K., GitHub Repo

Senior CS Capstone Project, sponsored by Invoca

- · Worked in a team of six to develop an Express web application deployed on Heroku to be used by salespeople.
- · Our multi-cloud solution displays critical call information in a single view.
- · Transcriptions generated by IBM Watson in near real-time retain important call details.
- · We leverage NLP Cloud to generate concise call summaries so that salespeople can easily remember call contents.
- · Keywords and the customer's sentiment are determined using Google Cloud's NLP API to guide sales follow-ups.
- We integrate Invoca's APIs service to retrieve call transcripts and store the data in a MongoDB database.
- We maintained well-documented code bases with version control, and touched base with mentors weekly and with team members daily.



Mar 2021 - Jun 2021

UCSB Courses Search, Application

Project for CMPSC 156: Advanced Applications Programming

- Worked with a team of ~20 people on this legacy project, a web application used to search for classes based on input criteria.
- · Worked closely with a team of 5 people to focus on improving the search user interface.

React Heroku Spring Boot Auth0 GitHub Agile Development

Feb 2021 - Mar 2021

Vision Test, Project Page

Project for ECE 153B: Sensor and Peripheral Interface Design

- · Designed a "vision test" that simulates a tumbling E chart with symbols gradually decreasing in size.
- · The E's are displayed on an 8x8 LED Matrix and a user inputs the direction that the E is facing using a Wii Nunchuk.
- A distance sensor will verify that the user is standing at an appropriate distance from the display.
- · A terminal will display the user's vision score.
- · Both the 8x8 LED Matrix and the Wii Nunchuk communicate with an STM32 microcontroller using I2C.
- · The terminal communicates with an STM32 microcontroller using SPI.

C STM32 Microcontroller 12C SPI Peripherals Product Design

Jan 2021 - Feb 2021

COVID-19 Survival Naive Bayes Classifier, GitHub Repo

Project for CMPSC 165A: Artificial Intelligence

- Designed a Naive Bayes Classifier in Python that determines whether a patient will survive from COVID-19 given their preconditions.
- · Preprocessed and cleansed training and validation data sets using NumPy and SciPy.
- · Built a model to determine which data fields were of greater importance.
- · Placed second on the class leader board for classification accuracy and runtime.

Artificial Intelligence | Machine Learning | Python | NumPy | SciPy | Data Processing | Modeling

Education

University of California, Santa Barbara, Santa Barbara, CA

Master of Science in Computer Science

- GPA: 4.0/4.0
- Programs: 5-year B.S./M.S. Program in Computer Science
- · Coursework in: Scalable Internet Services, Augmented Reality, Computer Graphics, Operating Systems, Runtime Systems
- Extracurricular Activities: Four Eyes Lab (Pursuing research in human-computer interaction, computer vision, and augmented reality),
 UCSB Badminton Club

Sep 2018 - Mar 2022

Universtiy of California, Santa Barbara, Santa Barbara, CA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

- GPA: 3.7/4.0
- Programs: College of Engineering Honors Program, 5-year B.S./M.S Program in Computer Science
- Coursework in: Data Structures and Algorithms, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Computer Vision, Digital Image Processing,
 Operating Systems, Network Computing, Advanced Applications Programming, Object-Oriented Design, Sensor and Peripheral Interface Design
- Extracurricular Activities: Co-Founder and Vice President of UCSB Badminton Club (4 years)

Aug 2014 - Jun 2018

American High School, Fremont, CA

High School Diploma

- UC Weighted GPA: 4.50 (Uncapped), 4.14 (Capped)
- SAT I: 1560/1600
- SAT II Chemistry: 800/800
- SAT II Math L2: 800/800
- Relevant AP classes: AP Chemistry, AP Physics C, AP Biology, AP Calculus BC, AP Computer Science (in Java), and AP English Language and Composition